

Lisbon, Portugal

lc.sbg.92@gmail.com

926055458

https://www.linkedin.com/in/luisclara/

https://github.com/LuisClara92

https://luis-clara-webdeveloper.netlify.app/

K

#### **PROFILE**

In the past few years, I have had a few different experiences related to Biotechnology and Chemistry Engineer.

I recently changed my path, creating a new route for my future!

Why? Because after I started writing my 1st line of code, the feeling that I am doing something for the good of the community has become real!! I aim to be a full-stack developer with a lot of knowledge, strong skills.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## 09/2020 - present Lisbon, Portugal

#### Full-stack Developer Freelancer, Krow

- Create and setting SignUp, LogIn, and Authentication System;
- Create and setting DataBase for Users, Locations, and Memberships;
- Deploy of DB, Front, and Backend in DigitalOceans;
- Set translation in PT and EN:
- Set live chat and bot client support and CRM tool with Hubspot;
- Set a Payment system using Stripe;

# 01/2017 - 08/2020 Lisbon, Portugal

#### **Restaurant Manager, McDonald's**

- P&L Restaurant Control
- Operational Control
- People Management Department:
- Training of Team Managers and Employees
- Staff Hours and Need for Recruitment
- Shift Management:
- Staff: Team Organization and Guidance
- Products: Quality Control and HACCP
- Equipment: Operation and Maintenance needs

03/2015 - 08/2016 Fundão, Portugal

Food Quality and Safety Engineer, Casa Quintela



## PROJECTS

12/2020 - present

**Portfolio,** React js with some Redux concepts, and style with SCSS ☑

• An App created to show my skill and all my projects;

11/2020 – present	<b>Krow.works,</b> React and Node (JavaScript), style with SCSS ☑
11/2020 – 11/2020	Game Library (4h), React (JavaScript), style with Material-UI ☑
11/2020 - 11/2020	The requirements were the following:  • Fetch the API
	<ul> <li>Styling consistency across all pages</li> <li>Clean and valid code</li> </ul>
	Use of royalty-free resources only

#### 10/2020 - 11/2020

# **Rick and Morty App,** React (JavaScript) style with SCSS ☑

The requirements were the following:

- At least 4 to 6 components with consistent navigation
- Wireframes
- Component Tree
- SCRUM
- Git workflow
- Deploy to Github or Netlify

• Deploy to Github or Netlify

#### 10/2020 - 10/2020

# Flags around World, First React Project, style with CSS

The requirements were the following:

- At least 4 to 6 components with consistent navigation
- Wireframes (to be validated in the beginning)
- Styling consistency across all pages
- Clean and valid code
- Use of royalty-free resources only
- Deploy to GitHub or Netlify
- Explicit commit messages (atomic commits)

(*) HARD SKILLS				
JavaScript	• • • • •	CSS   SCSS	• • • • •	
Git   GitHub   Ubuntu	• • • • •	Bootstrap   Material-UI	• • • • •	
<b>React</b> Hooks   Context   Reducer	• • • • •	<b>Node.js   Express.js</b> MVC   Middlewares	• • • • •	
Redux	$\bullet$ $\circ$ $\circ$ $\circ$	MySQL	• • • • •	
REST API	• • • • •	Postman	• • • • •	
MVC	• • • • •	Test - Jest	• • • • •	
Cloud - DigitalOceans	• • • • •			
	⟨♥⟩ SOF	T SKILLS		
Project Management	• • • • •	Team Work	• • • • •	
Autonomous	• • • •	Time Management	• • • • •	
Problem Solver	• • • • •	Team Leader	• • • • •	

## **EDUCATION**

09/2020 - 02/2021

Full-stack JavaScript Web Developer, Wild Code School

Lisbon, Portugal

Primary Languages: Javascript

**Environments: Node.JS** 

Frameworks / Libraries: React.js | Express.js | Bootstrap | Scss

Databases: MySQL

Others: SCRUM | Git | Github | HTML | CSS | Figma | Miro

Exp: Client Projects | Working Remote

2010 - 2014

Covilhã, Portugal

**Biotechnology,** Universidade da Beira Interior



# **U** LANGUAGES

**Portuguese,** Native

**English,** Professional



## **INTERESTS**

**Current Self-Learning** 

Java

**Next to Learn** 

FrontEnd: Typescript, and React

Native

BackEnd: Phyton

Hobby

Judo, Futsal, and Lego